She isn't coming yet, Toto.
她没跟来了,托托
Did she hurt you?
她弄痛你了吗?
She tried to, didn't she?
她试着那么做,不是吗?
Come on. We'll go tell Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
快点.我们去告诉亨利叔叔和艾姆婶婶
Aunt Em!
艾姆婶婶!
Listen to what Miss Gulch did to Toto--
你听听看喀尔胥小姐对托托做的...
Dorothy, please! We're counting!
Dorothy, please! 桃乐丝,拜托!我们正在算东西!
-But she hit him-- -Don't bother us now, honey.
- 但她打它... - 现在别烦我们,甜心
The incubator's gone bad and we're likely to lose a lot of our chicks.
孵蛋器坏了,看来我们会损失许多小鸡
That poor little thing.
可怜的小东西
But Miss Gulch hit Toto with a rake...
但是喀尔胥小姐用耙打托托...
...because she says he chases her nasty old cat every day!
...因为她说托托每天都追逐着 她那只坏脾气的老猫!
--seventy. Dorothy, please!
...70只 桃乐丝,拜托!
But he doesn't do it every day! Just once or twice a week.
但它没有每天这样 不过一星做个两三次罢了
And he can't catch her old cat anyway. Now she says she'll--
而且它根本抓不到她的老猫 现在她说她会...
Dorothy! We're busy.
桃乐丝!我们正忙着啊
Oh, all right.
噢,好吧
-How's she coming? -Take it easy.
- 她怎样? - 不要急
You got my finger!
你压到我的手指了!
Why don't you get your finger out of the way?
你为什么不把你的手拿开?
-There you are. -Right on my finger!
- 你来了 - 就在我手指上!
Lucky it wasn't your head!
幸好不是你的头!
Zeke, what am l going to do about Miss Gulch? Just because Toto--
杰可,我要拿喀尔胥小姐怎么办? 就因为托托...
Listen, honey, l got them hogs to get in.
听着,甜心,我要去把猪只赶进去
You ain't using your head. You'd think you didn't have any brains.
你没用脑筋 你可能认为你根本没任何头脑
l have so got brains!
我脑筋好得很!
Why don't you use them?
那你怎么不用?
Don't go by Miss Gulch's place.
别经过喀尔胥小姐的地方
Then Toto won't get in her garden, and you won't get in no trouble.
那么托托就不会跑进她的花园 而你也不会有麻烦了
Oh, Hunk, you just won't listen, that's all.
噢,杭克,你根本没在听,算了吧
Well, your head ain't made of straw, you know.
你知道你的头脑可不是稻草做的
Get in there before l make a dime bank out of you!
快进去,在我把你们当廉价赌本前!
Listen, kid...
听着,孩子...
...are you gonna let that old Gulch heifer try and buffalo you?
...你想让老喀尔胥那小母牛恐吓你?
She ain't nothing to be afraid of. Have a little courage.
她并不是无所畏惧! 你要拿出点勇气来
l'm not afraid of her.
我才不怕她
Next time she squawks, walk up to her and spit in her eye.
下次她再口出恶言 走向她并且当面藐视她
That's what l'd do.
那正是我要做的
Help me, Zeke! Get me out of here!
帮帮我,杰可!把我弄出这里!
Help!
救命!
-Are you all right, Dorothy? -Yes, l'm all right.
- 你还好吧,桃乐丝? - 是的,我没事
l fell in and Zeke--
我掉进去,而杰可...
Why, Zeke, you're just as scared as l am!
喔,杰可,你就跟我一样害怕!
You gonna let a little pig make a coward out of you?
你会让只小猪把你变成懦夫吗?
Look at you--
看看你...
What's all this jabber-wapping when there's work to be done?
看这是什么聊天聚会啊 什么时候才会将工作做完?
l know three farm hands that'll be out of a job!
我就知道三个农夫做一件工作 是成不了事的
Dorothy was--
桃乐丝刚才...
l saw you tinkering with that contraption, Hickory.
我看见你用粗劣手法修补那机器 海格瑞
-You and Hunk get back to that wagon. -All right.
- 你和杭克回去马车哪里 - 好吧
But someday they'll erect a statue to me--
但有一天他们会为我立件雕像...
Well, don't start posing for it now.
好了,现在别又开始为那摆姿势了
Can't work on an empty stomach. Have some crullers.
空着肚子无法工作!拿些小煎饼吧
-Gosh, Mrs. Gale. -Just fried.
- 谢了,杰尔夫人 - 只是油煎的
You see, Dorothy toppled into the--
你看,桃乐丝掉到这...
lt's no place for Dorothy around a pigsty!
桃乐丝不该到猪舍附近玩的!
Feed those hogs before they worry themselves into anemia!
喂喂那些猪 在它们担心自己得了贫血之前!
Do you know what Miss Gulch said she was going to do to Toto?
你知道喀尔胥小姐说 她准备怎么对付托托吗?
-She said she'd-- -Stop imagining things.
- 她说她会... - 别再胡思乱想了
You're always in a fret over nothing. You just help us out today...
你总是自寻烦恼 你只要在今天帮我们解决困难...
...and find a place where you won't get into any trouble.
...还有找一个你不会有麻烦的地方
Someplace where there isn't any trouble.
一个没有任何麻烦的地方
Do you suppose there is such a place, Toto?
你认为真的有那样的地方吗,托托?
There must be.
一定有
lt's not a place you can get to by a boat or a train.
哪里不是搭船或火车能到达的地方
lt's far, far away.
那地方离这里很远
Behind the moon...
月亮之后...
...beyond the rain....
...雨水另边...
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
∮在彩虹之上∮
Way up high
∮有个高高的地方∮
There's a land that I heard of
∮有一处我曾听说的乐土∮
Once in a lullaby
∮在摇篮曲中∮
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
∮在彩虹之上∮
Skies are blue
∮天空湛蓝∮
And the dreams that you dare to dream
∮只要你敢于梦想∮
Really do come true
∮这儿美梦都会成真∮
Someday I'll wish upon a star
∮有天我将对着星星许愿∮
And wake up where the clouds are far behind me
∮并在高高的云端醒来∮
Where troubles melt like lemon drops
∮一个烦恼都像 柠檬糖般融化的地方∮
Away above the chimney tops
∮在烟囱顶上高高之处∮
That's where you'll...
∮就在哪里你将会...∮
...find me
∮...找到我∮
Somewhere Over the Rainbow
∮在彩虹之上∮
Bluebirds fly
∮青鸟飞翔之处∮
Birds fly Over the Rainbow
∮鸟儿们飞越彩虹∮
Why then...
∮那么为什么...∮
...oh, why can't I?
∮...噢,为什么我不能?∮
If happy little bluebirds fly
∮如果快乐的小青鸟飞翔∮
Beyond the rainbow
∮在彩虹的那端∮
Why, oh, why...
∮为什么,噢,为什么...∮
...can't I?
∮...我不能?∮
Mr. Gale.
杰尔
Howdy, Miss Gulch.
你好,喀尔胥小姐
l want to see you and your wife about Dorothy.
我必须和你和你的太太谈谈桃乐丝
-What has Dorothy done? -What's she done?
- 桃乐丝做了什么? - 她做了什么?
l'm all but lame from the bite on my leg!
我全身都好,除了我的脚被咬变跛之外
-You mean, she bit you? -No, her dog!
- 你是说她咬你? - 不,是她的狗!
She bit her dog, eh?
她咬她的狗?
No.
不是
That dog's a menace. l'm taking him to make sure he's destroyed.
那条狗是个威胁 我要捕捉它,以确定它被毁灭
Destroyed! Toto?
毁灭!托托?
Oh, you can't! You mustn't!
噢,你不能!你不会吧!
Auntie Em! Uncle Henry! You won't let her, will you?
艾姆婶婶!亨利叔叔! 你们不会让她这么做吧,会吗?
Of course we won't.
当然我们不会
Will we, Em?
我会吗,艾姆?
Please, Aunt Em!
拜托,艾姆婶婶!
Toto didn't know he was doing anything wrong.
托托根本不知道它做错了什么
l'm the one that ought to be punished. Send me to bed without supper.
我才是应该被处罚的人 罚我上床并不准吃晚餐
Hand over that dog or l'll bring a suit that'll take your farm!
交出那只狗,否则我会告你 让你失去你的农场
The law protects folks against dogs that bite!
狗咬人违反法律对人的保障!
How about if she ties him up? He's gentle.
要她把它绑起来如何? 它很温和的
-With gentle people, that is. -That's for the sheriff to decide.
- 对仁慈的人来说,那就够了 - 那要由警长来决定
This order allows me to take him. Unless you want to go against the law.
这命令允许我带走它 除非你想违抗法律
We can't go against the law. l'm afraid Toto has to go.
我们不会违抗法律 我很遗憾托托必须被带走
Now you're seeing reason.
现在你了解原因了
Here's what l'm taking him in, so he can't attack me again.
我要它放在这里好带走 这样它就无法攻击我
l won't let you take him!
我不会让你带走它!
You go away!
你走开!
l'll bite you myself!
我会亲自咬你的!
You wicked old witch! Uncle Henry, Auntie Em, don't let her take Toto!
你这邪恶的老巫婆!亨利叔叔, 艾姆婶婶,别让她带走托托!
l've got an order! Let me have him!
我有许可证!把它给我!
Put him in the basket, Henry.
把它放进篮子里,亨利
-The idea! -Don't, Uncle Henry.
- 多明理! - 不要,亨利叔叔
Oh, Toto!
噢,托托!
Almira Gulch, just because you own half the county...
艾米拉.喀尔胥 就因为你拥有半个郡...
...doesn't mean you can run the rest of us!
...并不代表你可以支配我们!
For 23 years l've been dying to tell you what l thought of you!
23年来我一直忍耐着 不想告诉你,我对你的看法
And now--
而现在...
Well, being a Christian woman, l can't say it!
好吧,身为基督徒女子 我不能将那说出口!
Toto, darling!
托托,亲爱的!
l got you back!
我又得到你了!
You came back!
你回来了!
l'm so glad!
我真高兴!
They'll be coming back for you in a minute.
他们会马上到这里来抓你
We've got to get away!
我们必须离开!
We've got to run away!
我们得离家出走!
Well, well, well! Houseguests, eh?
喔,喔,喔!过夜的访客?
And who might you be?
你会是怎样的人呢?
No, no. Now, don't tell me.
不,不.现在别告诉我!
Let's see.
让我们瞧瞧
You're traveling in disguise.
你正在乔装旅行中
No, that's not right.
不,不是那样
You're going on a visit.
你正要去拜访某人
No, l'm wrong.
不,我想那不对
You're running away.
你离家出走了
How did you guess?
你怎么猜出来的?
Professor Marvel never guesses. He knows!
马勃尔教授从不用猜的,他就是知道!
Now, why are you running away?
现在,为什么你会离家出走?
No, no. Now, don't tell me.
不,不.别告诉我
They don't understand you at home. They don't appreciate you.
在家中他们不了解你 他们不知感激你
You want to see other lands. Big cities, big mountains, big oceans.
你想见识其他地方 大城市,大山,大海
Why, it's just like you could read what was inside of me.
为什么会这样 好像你能读出我的内心想法
Toto, that's not polite! We haven't been asked yet.
托托,那很不礼貌! 我们还没被邀请呢
He's perfectly welcome.
它是受欢迎的
As one dog to another, huh?
就像只狗对待另只狗般,哼?
Here now, where were we...?
现在,我们说到哪了..?
Why can't we go with you and see the crowned heads of Europe?
为什么我们不能跟着你 去看看欧洲的君王们?
Do you know any? Oh, you mean the thing....
你有认识的? 噢,你是说那回事...
l never do anything without consulting my crystal first.
没先问过我的水晶之前 我是不会做任何事的
Let's go inside here. We'll--
我们进去吧,我们会...
Just come along. l'll show you.
进来吧,我会做给你看的
That's right. Here.
这就对了,这里
Sit right down here.
就坐在这里
That's it.
那就是它
This is the same genuine, magic, authentic crystal...
这是同样血统,魔力,可靠的水晶...
...used by the priests of lsis and Osiris in the days of the Pharaohs...
...被奥西利斯及爱色斯神的祭司们 用于法老王之祭典日...
...in which Cleopatra saw the approach of Julius Caesar and Marc Anthony.
...埃及艳后用来看见 凯撒及安东尼逼近的水晶
And so on, and so on.
诸如此类等等
Now, you'd better close your eyes, my child, for a moment...
你现在最好闭上你的眼楮一下子...
...in order to be better in tune with the lnfinite.
...为了能跟造物主协调一致
We can't do these things without reaching out into the lnfinite.
我们若没办法接触造物主的话 是无法完成这些事的
Yes, that's all right.
好了,可以了
Now you can open them. We'll gaze into the crystal.
现在你可以睁开眼楮了 我们将凝视着水晶内部
What's this l see? A house with a picket fence...
我看见的是什么? 一间有尖木桩篱笆的房子...
...and a barn with a weathervane...
...还有一间有风向标的谷仓...
...of a running horse.
...及一匹跑动的马
That's our farm!
那是我们的农场!
There's a woman.
哪里有位女士
She's wearing a polka-dot dress. Her face is careworn.
她穿着件圆点花样的连身裙 她的表情看起来忧心忡忡的
That's Aunt Em.
那是艾姆婶婶
Yes, her name is Emily.
是的,她的名字是艾莫莉
That's right. What's she doing?
对.她在做什么?
Well, l can't quite see.
嗯,我没办法看得很清楚
Why, she's crying.
为什么?她正在哭!
Someone has hurt her.
有人伤害了她
Someone has just about broken her heart.
有人令她伤心
Me?
我?
Well, it's someone she loves very much.
喔,那是她所深爱的人
Someone she's been very kind to.
某个她非常慈爱对待的人
Someone she's taken care of in sickness.
某个在生病时她会悉心照顾的人
l had the measles once, and she stayed right by me every minute.
我有次得了麻疹 她片刻不离的待在我身边
What's she doing now?
现在她在做什么?
Yes, she's--
好的,她正...
What's this?
这是什么?
Why, she's putting her hand on her heart!
为什么?她将手放在她的心上
She's dropping down on the bed!
她正对着床掉眼泪!
Well, that's all. The crystal's gone dark.
哦,就这样了!水晶球已经变暗了
You don't suppose she could really be sick, do you?
你不会认为她真的病了吧,你会吗?
-l've got to go home right away! -l thought you were going with me.
- 我必须马上回家! - 我还以为你要跟我走
No, l have to get to her right away!
不,我必须马上回到她身边
Come on, Toto! Come on!
快点,托托!快点!
Goodbye, Professor Marvel. And thanks a lot!
再见,马勃尔教授,真是谢谢你!
Better get under cover, Sylvester. A storm's blowing up.
最好找个地方躲起来,史尔摩斯特 有个风暴来袭了
A whopper, to speak in the vernacular of the peasantry.
如果用农民的话来形容 那真是个滔天大谎
Poor little kid. l hope she gets home all right.
可怜的小孩,我希望她能平安到家
Get them horses loose!
把那些马松开!
Where's Hickory? Hickory!
海格瑞在哪里?海格瑞!
Doggone it!
该死的!
lt's a twister! lt's a twister!
那是个龙卷风!那是个龙卷风!
Dorothy!
桃乐丝!
Everybody in the storm cellar!
每个人都进去防风地窖!
Henry, l can't find Dorothy! She's out in the storm!
亨利,我找不到桃乐丝! 她在外面,在暴风圈内!
We can't look for her now.
我们现在无法去找她
Come on, get in the cellar! Hurry up!
快点,进去防风地窖!快一点!
Auntie Em!
艾姆婶婶!
Uncle Henry!
亨利叔叔!
We must be up inside the cyclone!
我们一定是在龙卷风里面!
Miss Gulch!
喀尔胥小姐!
Toto...
托托...
...l have a feeling we're not in Kansas anymore.
...我感觉我们已经不在堪萨斯了
We must be over the rainbow!
我们一定已经飞越了彩虹!
Now l know we're not in Kansas.
现在我知道我们真的不在堪萨斯了
Are you a good witch or a bad witch?
你是个好巫婆或坏巫婆?
Who, me?
谁,我吗?
l'm not a witch at all.
我根本不是巫婆
l'm Dorothy Gale, from Kansas.
我是桃乐丝.杰尔,从堪萨斯来的
ls that the witch?
它是不是巫婆?
Who, Toto? Toto's my dog.
谁,托托?托托是我的狗
l'm a little muddled. The Munchkins called me because a new witch...
我有点头昏脑涨的! 蛮支金呼叫我,因为一个新巫婆...
...just dropped a house on the Wicked Witch of the East.
...刚把间房子掉在东方坏巫婆身上
And there's the house, and here you are...
而哪里有间房子,还有你在这里...
...and that's all that's left of the Wicked Witch of the East.
...而那些就是东方坏巫婆留下的
What the Munchkins want to know is, are you a good witch or a bad witch?
蛮支金想知道 你是好巫婆还是坏巫婆?
But l've already told you, l'm not a witch at all.
但是我已经告诉过你 我根本不是巫婆
Witches are old and ugly.
巫婆都是又老又丑
What was that?
那是什么?
The Munchkins. They're laughing because l am a witch.
蛮支金们 他们正在笑,因为我就是个巫婆
l'm Glinda, the Witch of the North.
我叫葛琳达,是北方巫婆
You are?
你是?
l beg your pardon!
请原谅!
But l've never heard of a beautiful witch.
但是我从未听过有美丽的巫婆
Only bad witches are ugly.
只有坏巫婆才是丑陋的
The Munchkins are happy...
蛮支金们很高兴...
...because you freed them from the Wicked Witch of the East.
...因为你从东方坏巫婆手里 解救了他们
But if you please, what are Munchkins?
但如果你乐意的话 能告诉我"蛮支金"是什么吗?
The little people who live here. lt's Munchkinland...
生活在这里的小矮人 这里是蛮支金国...
...and you are their national heroine.
...而你是他们的国家女英雄
lt's all right. You may all come out and thank her.
没关系了,你们可以出来并谢谢她了
Come out, come out Wherever you are
∮出来,出来吧,不管你们在哪里∮
And meet the young lady Who fell from a star
∮见见这位 从星星掉下来的年轻女士吧∮
She fell from the sky She fell very far
∮她从天上掉下来 她从很远的地方掉下来∮
And Kansas, she says Is the name of the star
∮还有堪萨斯, 她说那是星星的名字∮
Kansas, she says
∮堪萨斯,她说那是星星的名字∮
She brings you good news
∮她为你们带来了好消息∮
Or haven't you heard?
∮或者你们还没听说?∮
When she fell out of Kansas
∮当她从堪萨斯掉下来时∮
A miracle occurred
∮一个奇迹发生了∮
It really was no miracle What happened was just this
∮其实没有奇迹,只是就这样发生了∮
The wind began to switch The house to pitch
∮风开始转变,房子被抛掷∮
And suddenly the hinges Started to unhitch
∮突然间绞链开始松脱∮
Just then the Witch To satisfy an itch
∮接着一个巫婆赶着去实现个愿望∮
Went flying on her broomstick Thumbing for a hitch
∮坐在她的帚柄上飞过去∮ ∮有人比着大拇指请求搭便车∮
And oh, what happened then was rich
∮还有,噢,然后发生的实在太多∮
The house began to pitch The kitchen took a slitch
∮房子被开始抛掷,厨房产生了裂缝∮
It landed on the Wicked Witch In the middle of a ditch
∮它着陆在坏巫婆的水道中间∮
Which was not a healthy situation For the Wicked Witch
∮对坏巫婆来说那可不是个好境遇∮
The house began to pitch The kitchen took a slitch
∮房子被开始抛掷,厨房产生了裂缝∮
It landed on the Wicked Witch In the middle of a ditch
∮它着陆在坏巫婆的水道中间∮
Which was not a healthy situation For the Wicked Witch
∮对坏巫婆来说那可不是个好境遇∮
Who began to twitch And was reduced to just a stitch
∮谁开始在抽搐,而简化成一针∮
Of what was once the Wicked Witch
∮那曾经有个坏巫婆∮
We thank you very sweetly
∮我们要很甜蜜的谢谢你∮
For doing it so neatly
∮为了你将它处理得这么干净俐落∮
You've killed her so completely
∮你让她死得永不超生∮
That we thank you very sweetly
∮我们要很甜蜜的谢谢你∮
Let the joyous news be spread! The Wicked Old Witch at last is dead!
散播这快乐的消息吧! 邪恶的老巫婆终于死了!
Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead Which old witch? The Wicked Witch
∮叮-咚!巫婆死了 哪个老巫婆?坏巫婆∮
Ding-Dong! The Wicked Witch is dead
∮叮-咚!坏巫婆已经死了∮
Wake up, you sleepyhead Rub your eyes, get out of bed
∮醒醒,你这贪睡鬼 擦亮你的眼楮,离开你的床∮
Wake up, the Wicked Witch is dead
∮醒来吧,坏巫婆已经死了∮
She's gone where the goblins go Below, below, below
∮她去了小妖精去的地方 在下面,在下面,在下面∮
Yo-ho! Let's open up and sing And ring the bells out
∮呦-呵!让我们开怀并欢唱 并且摇响铃声∮
Ding-Dong! The merry-o Sing it high, sing it low
∮叮-咚!这欢乐 在高处欢唱,在低处欢唱∮
Let them know The Wicked Witch is dead
∮让他们知道这坏巫婆死了∮
As mayor of the Munchkin City
∮身为蛮支金市市长∮
In the county of the Land of Oz
∮在欧兹国土的郡城上∮
I welcome you most regally
∮我以对待帝王般的热诚来欢迎你∮
But we've got to verify it legally
∮但我们必须 以法律上的方式证实它∮
-To see -To see?
∮- 去目赌∮ ∮- 去目赌?∮
-If she -If she?
∮- 是否她∮ ∮- 是否她?∮
Is morally, ethically
∮确实的,合规定的∮
-Spiritually, physically -Positively, absolutely
∮- 精神上,生理上∮ ∮- 肯定地,绝对的∮
Undeniably and reliably dead
∮确凿无疑地,真实的死了∮
As coroner I must aver
∮身为验尸官,我必须宣告那是事实∮
I thoroughly examined her
∮我已经彻底的检验过她∮
And she's not only merely dead
∮而她不仅仅是死了∮
She's really most sincerely dead
∮她是从内到外的死透了∮
Then this is a Day of lndependence...
那么这是独立日...
...for all the Munchkins and their descendants.
...对所有蛮支金人及其子孙
lf any!
如果有的话!
Yes, let the joyous news be spread. The Wicked Old Witch at last is dead!
是的,让我们散播这快乐的消息吧! 这邪恶的老巫婆终于死了!
Ding-Dong! The Witch is Dead Which old witch? The Wicked Witch
∮叮-咚!巫婆死了 哪个老巫婆?坏巫婆∮
Ding-Dong! The Wicked Witch is dead
∮叮-咚!坏巫婆已经死了∮
Wake up, you sleepyhead Rub your eyes, get out of bed
∮醒醒,你这贪睡鬼 擦亮你的眼楮,离开你的床∮
Wake up The Wicked Witch is dead
∮醒来吧,坏巫婆已经死了∮
She's gone where the goblins go Below, below, below
∮她去了小妖精去的地方 在下面,在下面,在下面∮
Yo-ho! Let's open up and sing And ring the bells out
∮呦-呵!让我们开怀并欢唱 并且摇响铃声∮
Ding-Dong! The merry-o Sing it high, sing it low
∮叮-咚!这欢乐 在高处欢唱,在低处欢唱∮
Let them know the Wicked Witch is dead
∮让他们知道这坏巫婆死了∮
We represent the Lullaby League
∮我们代表摇篮联盟∮
The Lullaby League
∮摇篮联盟∮
And in the name of the Lullaby League
∮以摇篮联盟之名∮
We wish to welcome you To Munchkinland
∮我们竭诚欢迎你到蛮之金国∮
We represent the Lollipop Guild
∮我们代表棒棒糖协会∮
The Lollipop Guild
∮棒棒糖协会∮
And in the name of the Lollipop Guild
∮以棒棒糖协会之名∮
We wish to welcome you To Munchkinland
∮我们竭诚欢迎你到蛮之金国∮
We welcome you to Munchkinland
∮我们欢迎你到蛮之金国∮
From now on you'll be history
∮从今以后你将会名留青史∮
-You'll be his-- -You'll be history
∮- 你将会...∮ ∮- 你将会名留青史∮
And we will glorify your name
∮我们将赞美你的名字∮
-You will be a bust -Be a bust
∮- 你将被塑造成半身雕像∮ ∮- 做成半身雕像∮
-In the hall of fame
∮- 在名望大厅中∮
l thought you said she was dead.
我以为你说过她死了
That was her sister, the Wicked Witch of the East.
死的她的姊姊,东方坏巫婆
This is the Wicked Witch of the West. She's worse than the other one was.
这个是西方坏巫婆 她比另一个坏多了
Who killed my sister? Who killed the Witch of the East?
谁杀了我姊姊?谁杀了东方巫婆?
Was it you?
是你吗?
lt was an accident. l didn't mean to kill anybody.
那是个意外.我并未存心杀死任何人
Well, my little pretty, l can cause accidents too!
好吧,我了小美人 我也可以引发些意外的
-Aren't you forgetting the ruby slippers? -The slippers. Yes!
- 你忘了红宝石鞋吗? - 红鞋.对!
The slippers!
红鞋!
They're gone!
它们不见了!
The ruby slippers! What have you done with them?
那对红宝石鞋!你对它们做了什么?
Give them back to me or l'll--
把它们还我,否则我会...
lt's too late! There they are, and there they'll stay!
太迟了!它们在那,而且会留在哪里!
Give me back my slippers! Only l know how to use them.
把我的红鞋还我! 只有我知道如何使用它们
They're of no use to you. Give them back to me. Give them back!
它们对你没有用!把它们还我,还我!
Keep inside of them.
穿着它们
Their magic must be powerful or she wouldn't want them so badly.
它们的魔力一定很强大 否则她不会这么想要它们
Stay out of this, Glinda, or l'll fix you as well!
别插手这事,葛琳达 要不然我连你一起修理!
Oh, rubbish! You have no power here.
噢,废话!你在这里根本没法力
Begone, before somebody drops a house on you too.
走吧, 在某人弄间房子也掉在你身上之前
Very well. l'll bide my time.
很好!我会等待我的时机的
And as for you, it's true l can't attend to you here and now as l'd like.
而对你,我是真的无法在这里 如我所愿的对付你
But just try to stay out of my way!
但是试着别档我的路!
Just try!
只是试试!
l'll get you, my pretty...
我会抓到你的,我的小美人...
...and your little dog too!
...还有你的狗!
lt's all right. You can get up. She's gone!
没事了.你们可一起来了,她走了!
lt's all right.
没关系了
You can all get up.
你们全部的人都可以起来了
What a smell of sulfur!
这硫磺烟雾臭死了!
l'm afraid you've made an enemy of the Wicked Witch.
我担心你已经成了坏巫婆的敌人
The sooner you get out of Oz altogether, the safer you'll sleep, my dear.
你们必须尽早离开欧兹国土 那你才能安心睡觉,我亲爱的
Oh, l'd give anything to get out of Oz altogether.
噢,我愿付出任何东西来换取 让我们离开欧兹国土
But which is the way back to Kansas? l can't go the way l came.
但是哪条路能回到堪萨斯? 我可无法从原路回去
No, that's true. The only person who might know...
是的,那倒是真的! 只有一个人可能知道...
...would be the great and wonderful Wizard of Oz himself.
...那是伟大而神奇的欧兹大法师
The Wizard of Oz? ls he good or is he wicked?
欧兹大法师?他是好的或是坏的?
Oh, very good, but very mysterious.
噢,非常的好,但是非常的神秘
He lives in the Emerald City, a long journey from here.
他居住在翡翠城,离这里很远的路程
Did you bring your broomstick with you?
你能用你的扫帚带我跟着你去吗?
No, l'm afraid l didn't.
不,恐怕不行
Well, then, you'll have to walk.
嗯,现在,你将必须徒步前去
The Munchkins will see you to the border of Munchkinland.
蛮支金人会照顾你到蛮支金国边界
And remember, never let those ruby slippers off your feet for a moment...
还有记住让红鞋与你片刻不离...
...or you will be at the mercy of the Wicked Witch of the West.
...否则你将可要祈求西方坏巫婆 的怜悯了
But how do l start for Emerald City?
但是我要怎么开始到翡翠城呢?
lt's always best to start at the beginning.
从起点开始总是最好的
And all you do is follow the Yellow Brick Road.
你所要做的就是跟随着黄砖路
-But what happens if l-- -Just follow the Yellow Brick Road.
- 但那会发生什么,如果我... - 只要跟随着黄砖路
-Goodbye!
- 再见!
My!
我的天!
People come and go so quickly here!
在这里的人们来去都这们匆忙!
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
∮跟随着黄砖路∮
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
∮跟随着黄砖路?∮
Follow, follow, follow, follow Follow the Yellow Brick Road
∮跟随着,跟随着,跟随着,跟随着∮ ∮跟随着黄砖路∮
You're Off to See the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮你要出发去见大法师 神奇的欧兹大法师∮
You'll find he is a whiz of a wiz If ever a wiz there was
∮你会发现他是天才中的天才 如果未曾有过这样的天才∮
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was The Wizard of Oz is one because
∮如果未曾,如果未曾有过这样的天才 那欧兹大法师就是一个,因为∮
Because, because, because Because, because
∮因为,因为,因为,因为,因为∮
Because of the wonderful things he does
∮因为他所做的神奇美妙的事情∮
You're Off to See the Wizard The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮你要出发去见大法师 那神奇的欧兹大法师∮
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
跟随着黄砖路?
Follow the Yellow...?
跟随着黄...?
Now which way do we go?
现在我该走哪条路?
Pardon me! That way is a very nice way.
抱歉!那条是非常好的路
Who said that?
谁那么说的?
Don't be silly, Toto. Scarecrows don't talk.
别蠢了,托托!稻草人不会说话
lt's pleasant down that way too.
走那条路也一样让人愉快
That's funny. Wasn't he pointing the other way?
真好笑,他刚才不是指着另一条路吗?
Of course, people do go both ways.
当然,人们会走这两条路的
Why, you did say something, didn't you?
喔,你真的说了些事,不是吗?
Are you doing that on purpose, or can't you make up your mind?
你是故意那样做的 还是你没办法做决定?
That's the trouble. l can't make up my mind.
那就是麻烦所在,我没办法做决定!
l haven't got a brain.
我没得到个头脑!
Only straw.
只有稻草
How can you talk if you haven't got a brain?
如果你没头脑,你怎么能说话?
l don't know.
我不知道
But some people without brains do a lot of talking, don't they?
但是有些人不也是不用头脑 就能说一大些废话,不是吗?
Yes, l guess you're right.
是的,我想你是对的
Well, we haven't really met properly, have we?
哦,我们还没正式认识吧,对吗?
Why, no.
当然,没有
How do you do?
你好吗?
-Very well, thank you. -l'm not feeling at all well.
- 很好,谢谢你 - 我一点都不觉得好
lt's very tedious being stuck up here all day long with a pole up your back.
整天跟背后的这根柱子一起 一直卡在这里真是使人厌烦
Oh, dear. That must be terribly uncomfortable. Can't you get down?
噢,亲爱的.那一定很不舒服! 你不能下来吗?
Down? No, you see, l'm-- Well, l'm--
下来?不行,你看,我... 嗯,我...
Well, here. Let me help you.
喔,这里.让我来帮你
That's very kind of you. Very kind.
你真是好心,非常好心
Oh, dear. l don't see....
噢,亲爱的.我没看到...
Of course, l'm not bright about doing things...
当然,关于做事我不是很机灵...
...but if you'll just bend the nail down, maybe l'll slip off and--
...但是如果你将钉子折弯的话 也许我可以滑下去,并且...
Oh, yes!
噢,是的!
There goes some of me again!
这里又有些从我身体里跑出来了!
Does it hurt you?
那会弄痛你吗?
l just keep picking it up and putting it back in again.
噢,不会! 我只要捡起它,再把它摆回去
My! lt's good to be free!
我的天!自由的感觉真好!
Did l scare you?
我吓着你了吗?
l just thought you hurt yourself.
我只是以为你伤害到你自己
l didn't scare you?
我没吓着你?
No, of course not.
不,当然没有
l didn't think so.
我可不那么认为
Boo! Scat! Boo!
噗!史科特!噗!
You see? l can't even scare a crow.
你看到没?我连只乌鸦也吓不了
They come from miles around just to eat in my field and laugh in my face.
它们从几哩附近飞来我的田里吃东西 还讥笑我的脸
Oh, l'm a failure, because l haven't got a brain!
噢,我是个失败者 因为我没有个头脑!
What would you do with a brain if you had one?
如果你有个头脑你会怎么做?
Do? Why, if l had a brain, l could--
做?当然,如果我有个头脑,我可能...
I could while away the hours Conferring with the flowers
∮我可能离开个几小时,跟花儿呢喃∮
Consulting with the rain
∮跟雨水交换意见∮
And my head I'd be scratchin' While my thoughts were busy hatchin'
∮当我搔搔我的头,灵感便泉涌∮
If I Only Had a Brain
∮只要我有个头脑∮
I'd unravel every riddle For any individ'le
∮我会解开每一个谜题∮ ∮为每一个陷入麻烦或痛苦的人∮
In trouble or in pain
∮有思想,你就能思考 你可以成为另一个林肯∮
With the thoughts you'd be thinkin' You could be another Lincoln
∮只要你有个头脑∮
If you only had a brain
∮噢,我能告诉你为什么∮
The ocean's near the shore
∮海洋会亲近海岸∮
I could think of things I never thunk before
∮我可以思考以往从未想过的事情∮
And then I'd sit And think some more
∮还有我会坐下来,并想得更多∮
I would not be just a nothin' My head all full of stuffin'
∮我将不会再一无所有 我的头恼充满了东西∮
My heart all full of pain
∮我的心满载着痛苦∮
I would dance and be merry Life would be a ding-a-derry
∮我会愉悦,跳舞 生命将是一首反复的民谣∮
If I Only Had a Brain
∮只要我有个头脑∮
Wonderful!
好极了!
lf our scarecrow back in Kansas could do that...
如果我们在堪萨斯的稻草人 能那样做...
-...the crows would be scared to pieces! -They would?
- ...那乌鸦们会吓成碎片! - 它们会?
-Where's Kansas? -That's where l live.
- 堪萨斯在哪里? - 那是我住的地方
l want to get back there so badly, l'm going to Emerald City...
我非常想回去哪里! 我正要去翡翠城...
...to get the Wizard of Oz to help me.
...去请求欧兹大法师帮助我
You're going to see a wizard?
你正要去见一个大法师?
Do you think if l went, this wizard would give me brains?
你认为如果我去的话 大法师会给我头脑吗?
l couldn't say.
我不敢说
But even if he didn't, you'd be no worse off than you are now.
但即使他不能,你也不会比现在更糟
-Yes, that's true. -But maybe you better not.
- 对,那是真的 - 但也许你最好不要
l've got a witch mad at me, and you might get into trouble.
我让一个巫婆很生气 也许会让你惹上麻烦
Witch?
巫婆?
l'm not afraid of a witch! l'm not afraid of anything!
我不怕巫婆!我任何事都不怕!
Except a lighted match.
除了一跟点着了的火柴
l don't blame you.
我不怪你
But l'd face a whole box of them for the chance of getting some brains.
但是为了有机会取得头脑的话 我宁愿面对一整盒的火柴
l won't be any trouble, because l don't eat a thing.
我不会增添任何麻烦 因为我不必吃任何东西
And l won't try to manage things, because l can't think.
而且我也不会试着去操控事情 因为我不会思考
Won't you take me with you?
你愿意带我一起去吗?
Of course l will!
当然我愿意!
Hooray! We're off to see a wizard!
万岁!我们出发去见大法师吧!
-You're not starting out very well. -l'll try! Really, l will!
- 你出发得并不怎么顺利 - 我会试的!真的,我会!
-To Oz? -To Oz!
- 到欧兹? - 到欧兹!
We're Off to See the Wizard The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮我们出发去见大法师 神奇的欧兹大法师∮
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz If ever a wiz there was
∮你会发现他是天才中的天才 如果未曾有过这样的天才∮
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was The Wizard of Oz is one because
∮如果未曾,如果未曾有过这样的天才 那欧兹大法师就是一个,因为∮
Because, because, because Because, because
∮因为,因为,因为,因为,因为∮
Because of the wonderful things he does
∮因为他所做的神奇美妙的事情∮
We're Off to See the Wizard The Wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮我们出发去见大法师 神奇的欧兹大法师∮
Apples!
只果!
Oh, look!
噢,看啊!
What do you think you're doing?
你以为你在干嘛?
We've been walking a long ways and l was hungry and--
我们已经走了很长的一段路 而我感到很饥饿,还有...
Did you say something?
是你在说话吗?
-She was hungry!
- 她很饿!
How would like to have someone come along and pick something off of you?
喜欢有人跑来并从你身上拿走东西吗?
Oh, dear!
噢,哎呀!
l keep forgetting l'm not in Kansas.
我又忘了我不是在堪萨斯
Come along, Dorothy.
过来,桃乐丝
You don't want any of those apples.
你不会要那些只果的
Are you hinting my apples aren't what they ought to be?
你是在暗示我的只果 不是它们应有的模样?
Oh, you!
噢,你!
l'll show you how to get apples.
我会让你看怎样得到只果的
Hooray! l guess that did it!
万岁!我想它办到了!
Help yourself.
自个儿来吧
Why, it's a man!
当然,它是个人!
A man made out of tin!
用锡做的人!
Yes...!
是的...!
Look!
看!
Did you say something?
你说了什么吗?
He said "oilcan."
他说"油罐"
Oil can what?
什么是油罐头?
Oilcan?
油罐?
Here it is.
在这里
Where do you want to be oiled first?
你希望从哪里开始上油?
He said his mouth.
他说从嘴巴
The other side.
另一面
My goodness! l can talk again!
谢天谢地!我又能讲话了!
Oil my arms, please. Oil my elbows.
帮我的手臂上点油,拜托 肘部也上点
Here.
这里
Did that hurt?
那会痛吗?
No, it feels wonderful.
不会,那感觉好极了
l've held that axe up for ages.
我像这样握着斧头已经很久了
Goodness!
我的天!
How did you ever get like this?
你怎么会搞成那样子?
About a year ago...
大约一年前...
...l was chopping that tree...
...我正在砍着树...
...when suddenly it began to rain.
...突然间开始下起雨来
And right in the middle of a chop, l rusted solid.
就在砍到一半的时候,我就锈住了
And l've been that way ever since.
从那时我就保持那样直到现在
You're perfect now.
你现在很完美
My neck. My neck.
我的脖子.我的脖子
Perfect?
完美?
Bang on my chest if you think l'm perfect.
敲敲我的胸膛 如果你认为我是完美的
Go ahead, bang on it!
开始吧,敲敲它!
Beautiful!
美极了!
What an echo!
回音真棒!
lt's empty.
它是空的
The tinsmith forgot to give me a heart.
锡匠忘了给我一颗心
No heart?
没有心?
No heart.
没有心
All hollow.
所有都空的
When a man's an empty kettle He should be on his mettle
∮当一个人是个空水壶 他应该无所畏惧∮
And yet I'm torn apart
∮而我却悲伤莫名∮
Just because I'm presumin' That I could be kind of human
∮因为我认为 我可以成为人类∮
If I Only Had a Heart
∮只要我有颗心∮
I'd be tender, I'd be gentle And awful sentimental
∮会很温柔,我会是文质彬彬 而且非常多愁善感的∮
Regarding love and art
∮关于爱及艺术∮
I'd be friends with the sparrows And the boy who shoots the arrows
∮我会与麻雀及丘比特为友∮
If I Only Had a Heart
∮只要我有颗心∮
Picture me A balcony
∮我想象 一座阳台∮
Above, a voice sings low
∮上面,有个声音低声吟唱∮
Wherefore art thou, Romeo?
∮你在哪里,罗密欧?∮
I hear a beat
∮我听到一阵心跳∮
How sweet!
多甜蜜啊!
Just to register emotion Jealousy, devotion
∮就让那情绪表达出来吧 不管是妒忌还是挚爱∮
And really feel the part
∮真正感受其中的滋味∮
I could stay young and chipper And I'd lock it with a zipper
∮我将能保持青春及活力充沛 而且我会用拉链将它锁藏起来∮
If I Only Had a Heart
∮只要我有颗心∮
-Are you all right? -l'm a little rusty yet.
- 你还好吧? - 我还有些不灵活
Oh, dear!
噢,亲爱的!
That was wonderful!
真是奇妙啊!
You know...
你知道...
...we were wondering why you couldn't come with us...
...我们在想为什么你不跟着我们...
...to ask the Wizard for a heart.
...去跟大法师要个心
Suppose the Wizard wouldn't give me one when we got there.
如果当我们到达哪里 大法师却不能给我一个心呢?
Oh, but he will!
噢,但他会的!
He must!
他一定要!
We've come such a long way already.
我们已经走了这么远的一段路
You call that long?
你称那叫"远"?
Why, you've just begun!
哎呀,你们才刚开始罢了!
Helping the little lady along, are you, my fine gentlemen?
一起帮这小女士,好吗,我的好绅士?
Well, stay away from her...
嗯,离她远些...
...or l'll stuff a mattress with you!
...否则我会拿你来填床垫!
And you!
还有你!
l'll use you for a beehive!
我会用你当蜂窝!
Here, scarecrow! Want to play ball?
接着,稻草人!要玩球吗?
l'm not afraid of her.
我才不怕她
l'll see you get safely to the Wizard, whether l get a brain or not!
我会照顾你直到见着大法师 不管我会不会得到个头脑!
Stuff a mattress with me!
拿我填床垫?!
l'll see you reach the Wizard, whether l get a heart or not.
我会照顾你直到到达大法师哪里 不管我会不会得到个心!
Beehive! Bah!
当蜂窝!呸!
Let her try and make a beehive out of me!
让她试试用我来做蜂窝吧!
You're the best friends anybody ever had.
你们是任何人一生 所能拥有的最好的朋友
And it's funny, but l feel as if l've known you all the time.
那有趣的是 我觉得我已经认识你们一辈子了
-But l couldn't have, could l? -l don't see how.
- 但我之前没可能见过你们,可能吗? - 我不知道怎么会那样
You weren't around when l was stuffed and sewn together.
当我被填充并缝制的时候 你并不在附近
And l was standing over there rusting for the longest time.
而我生锈站在哪里一段很长的时间
Still, l wish l could remember.
尽管如此,我希望我可以记得
But l guess it doesn't matter anyway.
但是我想那并没有关系
We know each other now.
我们现在彼此认识了
-That's right. -We do.
- 对极了 - 是啊
-To Oz? -To Oz!
- 到欧兹? - 到欧兹!
We're Off to See the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮我们出发去见大法师 神奇的欧兹大法师∮
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz If ever a wiz there was
∮我们听说他是天才中的天才 如果未曾有过这样的天才∮
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was The Wizard of Oz is one because
∮如果未曾,如果未曾有过这样的天才 那欧兹大法师就是一个,因为∮
Because, because, because Because, because
∮因为,因为,因为,因为,因为∮
Because of the wonderful things he does
∮因为他所做的神奇美妙的事情∮
We're Off to See the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮我们出发去见大法师 神奇的欧兹大法师∮
l don't like this forest.
我不喜欢这森林
lt's dark and creepy!
它阴暗而且令人毛骨悚然!
Of course, l don't know...
当然,我不知道...
...but l think it'll get darker before it gets lighter.
...但是我想在它变亮之前 它会越来越暗
Do you suppose we'll meet any wild animals?
你想我们会碰上什么野兽吗?
We might.
可能会
Animals that eat straw?
有吃稻草的野兽吗?
Some, but mostly lions and tigers and bears.
有些,但大部分的野兽是狮子,老虎和熊
-Lions! -And tigers?
- 狮子! - 还有老虎?
And bears!
还有熊!
Lions and tigers and bears! Oh, my!
狮子,老虎和熊!噢,我的天!
Put 'em up! Put 'em up!
把手臂抬起来!把手臂抬起来!
Which one of you first?
你们谁先上?
l'll fight you both together, if you want.
我可以让你们两个一起来 如果你们希望
l'll fight you with one paw tied behind my back!
我可以将一只脚掌绑在背后跟你们打!
l'll fight you on one foot!
我可以用一只脚跟你们打!
l'll fight you with my eyes closed!
我可以闭着眼楮跟你们打!
Pulling an ax on me, eh?
拔出斧头来对付我,哼?
Sneaking up on me, eh? Why....
偷袭我,哼?当然...
-Go away and let us alone. -Oh, scared, huh?
- 走开,别烦我们 - 噢,害怕了,哼?
Afraid, huh?
害怕,哼?
How long can you stay fresh in that can?
你在罐头里能保持新鲜多久呢?
Come on, get up and fight, you shivering junkyard.
快点,起来和战斗吧 你这颤抖的废物堆积场
Put your hands up, you lopsided bag of hay!
抬起你的手,你这歪斜的干草袋!
That's getting personal, Lion.
那是人身攻击,狮子
Yes, get up and teach him a lesson.
是啊,起来并给它个教训
What's wrong with you teaching him?
对教训它,你有什么问题?
Well, l hardly know him.
嗯,我很难了解他
l'll get you anyway, peewee!
我一定会抓到你的,小东西!
Shame on you!
你真是丢脸!
What did you do that for? l didn't bite him.
你为什么要那样做? 我又没有咬它
No, but you tried to.
没有,但你试着去做
lt's bad enough picking on a straw man, but picking on little dogs....
找稻草人的碴就已经很糟糕了 不用再说去找只小狗的碴...
Well, you didn't have to go and hit me, did you?
喔,你也不必跑来打我,不是吗?
ls my nose bleeding?
我的鼻子在流血吗?
Well, of course not.
当然没有
My goodness, what a fuss you're making!
我的天,都是你小题大作害的!
Naturally, when you go around picking on things weaker than you are....
当然,当你在附近找些 比你软弱的东西的碴...
You're nothing but a big coward!
你除了像个懦夫外,什么都不是!
You're right, l am a coward!
你是对的,我是个懦夫!
l haven't any courage at all.
我根本毫无勇气
l even scare myself!
我甚至会被自己吓到!
Look at the circles under my eyes.
看看我眼楮下的眼袋
l haven't slept in weeks.
我已经有几个星期没睡觉了
Why don't you try counting sheep?
难道你没有试着数羊吗?
That doesn't do any good. l'm afraid of them.
那没有任何帮助,我怕它们
Oh, that's too bad.
噢,那太糟了
You think the Wizard could help him too?
你想大法师也能帮它吗?
l don't see why not.
我看不出为什么不行
Come along with us.
跟我们一起来吧
We're on our way to see the Wizard. To get him a heart.
我们正要去见大法师 去帮他得到个心
-And him a brain. -He could give you some courage.
- 还有他的脑子 - 他可以给你一些勇气
Wouldn't you feel degraded to be seen in the company of a cowardly lion?
你们跟只胆小的狮子在一起 会不会觉得丢脸?
l would.
我会
No, of course not.
不,当然不会
Gee, that's awfully nice of you.
哇,你真是太好了
My life has been simply unbearable.
我的生命简直无法让人忍受下去了
Well, it's all right now.
哦,现在没关系了
The Wizard'll fix everything.
大法师将会解决每件事
lt's been in me so long.
我已经忍受很久了
l just gotta tell you how l feel.
我将告诉你我的感受
Come on!
快点!
Yeah, it's sad, believe me, missy When you're born to be a sissy
∮相信我,小姑娘,那真的很悲哀 当你天生胆小...∮
Without the vim and verve
∮...没有活力及激情∮
But I could show my prowess Be a lion, not a mouse
∮但我可以展现我的英勇无畏∮ ∮当一头雄狮,而不是一只老鼠∮
If I Only Had the Nerve
∮只要我有勇气∮
I'm afraid there's no denyin' I'm just a dandy lion
∮我恐怕无法否认 我只是头漂亮的狮子∮
A fate I don't deserve
∮我的命运不该如此∮
-I'd be brave as a blizzard -I'd be gentle as a lizard
∮我该像暴风雪般勇猛 我该像蜥蜴般高贵∮
I'd be clever as a gizzard
∮我该像沙囊般伶俐∮
If the Wizard is a wizard who will serve
∮如果我要找的大法师 真的是个巫师∮
Then I'm sure to get a brain
∮那我就能得到一个头脑∮
-A heart -A home
∮- 一个心∮ ∮- 一个家∮
The nerve!
∮勇气!∮
We're Off to See the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮我们出发去见大法师 神奇的欧兹大法师∮
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz If ever a wiz there was
∮我们听说他是天才中的天才 如果未曾有过这样的天才∮
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was The Wizard of Oz is one because
∮如果未曾,如果未曾有过这样的天才 那欧兹大法师就是一个,因为∮
Because, because, because Because, because
∮因为,因为,因为,因为,因为∮
Because of the wonderful things he does
∮因为他所做的神奇美妙的事情∮
We're Off to See the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
∮我们出发去见大法师 神奇的欧兹大法师∮
So you won't take warning, eh?
所以你们不想接受警告?
All the worse for you, then!
那对你们来说真是再糟不过了
l'll take care of you now instead of later!
我将会马上对付你们!
When l gain those ruby slippers...
当我获得那红宝石鞋...
...my power will be the greatest in Oz!
...我将会变成欧兹国最伟大的人
And now, my beauties...
现在,我的美人们...
...something with poison in it, l think.
...放点毒药到里头,我想
With poison in it.
家点毒药到里头
But attractive to the eye and soothing to the smell!
一定要能吸引眼楮的注意 以及闻起来让人昏昏欲睡!
Poppies.
罂粟
Poppies will put them to sleep.
罂粟会让他们睡着
Sleep....
睡着...
Now they'll sleep.
现在他们将会睡着
There's Emerald City!
那是翡翠城!
Oh, we're almost there! At last! At last!
噢,我们就要到了! 终于!终于啊!
lt's beautiful, isn't it? Just like l knew it would be.
它真是美丽,不是吗? 就跟我想的一样
He really must be a wonderful wizard to live in a city like that!
居住在像那样的地方 他一定真的是个神奇的大法师!
What are we waiting for?
我们还等什么?
-Nothing! Let's hurry! -Yes, let's run!
- 没事!大家快点! - 是呀,让我们用跑的!
Come on! Come on!
来吧!来吧!
Hurry! Hurry!
快点!快点!
Go! Look!
走啊!看!
Come on!
快点!
Look at the scenery. lt's wonderful!
看看这景色,真是美极了!
Emerald City!
翡翠城!
What's happening?
发生了什么事?
What is it?
那是什么?
l can't run anymore. l'm so sleepy.
我好想睡觉,我再也跑不动了
Give us your hands. We'll pull you.
把手给我们,我们会拉着你
Oh, no, please.
噢,不要,拜托
l have to rest for just a minute.
我必须休息一下子
Toto. Where's Toto?
托托.托托在哪里?
You can't rest now. We're nearly there.
你现在不能休息,我们离哪里很近了
Don't cry. You'll rust yourself again!
别哭!你会让你自己再次生锈的!
Coming to think of it, forty winks wouldn't be bad.
仔细想想,打个瞌睡也不错
Don't you start it too!
你不要也开始这样!
We ought to carry Dorothy!
我们应该背着桃乐丝!
l don't think l could, but we could try.
我不认为我行,但我们可以试试
Now look at him! lt's terrible!
现在看着他!那太可怕了!
Here, Tin Man, help me.
过来,锡人,帮帮我
This is terrible!
这真是太可怕了!
l can't budge her an inch! This is a spell, this is!
我无法移动她,连一寸都不能! 这是个咒语,一定是!
lt's the Wicked Witch! What'll we do?
那是坏巫婆做的!我们要怎么办?
Help! Help!
救命!救命!
lt's no use screaming at a time like this.
这这种时候像那样大喊是没有用的
Nobody will hear you! Help! Help!
没有人会听见的! 救命!救命!
Help!
救命!
lt's snowing!
下起雪来了!
No, it isn't!
不,那不是!
Yes, it is!
是的,那是!
Maybe that'll help!
也许那会有帮助!
Oh, but it couldn't help!
噢,但那不可能有帮助!
lt does help!
那有帮助!
Dorothy, you're waking up!
桃乐丝,你醒来了!
Unusual weather we're having, ain't it?
我们遇上了不寻常的天气,不是吗?
Look. He's rusted again!
看.他又锈住了!
-Give me the oilcan, quick! -Here.
- 把油灌给我,快点! - 这里
-He is rusted.
- 他锈住了 - 拿去
-Quick!
- 这里 - 快点!
Curses! Curses!
该死的!我诅咒她!
Somebody always helps that girl!
总是有人帮助那女孩!
But shoes or no shoes, l'm still great enough to conquer her.
不管有没有鞋子 我还是有足够的力量来征服她
And woe to those who try to stop me!
还有把灾难降给那些想阻止我的人
Let's get out of here.
让我们离开这里
Look! Emerald City is closer and prettier than ever!
看啊!翡翠城更近了,还比之前更漂亮!
You're out of the woods You're out of the dark
∮你们已经脱离了森林∮ ∮你们已经脱离了黑暗∮
You're out of the night
∮你们已经脱离了夜晚∮
Step into the sun Step into the light
∮步入了阳光之下∮ ∮步入了光明之中∮
Keep straight ahead for the most glorious place
∮笔直的前往这最辉煌的地方...∮
On the face of the earth or the sky
∮...无论从在天上或地上来看∮
Hold on to your breath Hold on to your heart
∮屏住你们的呼吸∮ ∮坚持你们的勇气∮
Hold on to your hope
∮紧握你们的期望∮
March up to the gate And bid it open
∮向着大门行军,命令它打开∮
To the Emerald City, as fast as lightning!
向着翡翠城而去,以闪电般的速度
You're out of the woods You're out of the dark
∮你们已经脱离了森林∮ ∮你们已经脱离了黑暗∮
You're out of the night
∮你们已经脱离了夜晚∮
Step into the sun Step into the light
∮步入了阳光之下∮ ∮步入了光明之中∮
March up to the gate And bid it...
∮向着大门行军,命令它...∮
...open
∮...打开∮
Open
∮打开∮
Who rang that bell?
是谁摇的铃?
-We did! -Can't you read?
- 是我们! - 你们没看见吗?
-Read what? -The notice!
- 看见什么? - 公告!
-What notice? -lt's on the door!
- 什么公告? - 那贴在门上的!
As plain as the nose on my face!
清楚得就像鼻子在我脸上一样!
"Bell out of order.
"摇铃是不合规定的
Please knock."
请敲门"
Well! That's more like it!
喔!这比较合规定!
Now, state your business.
现在,说明你们的来意
We want to see the Wizard!
我们想求见大法师!
The Wizard?
大法师?
But nobody can see the Great Oz!
没有人能见伟大的欧兹大法师!
Nobody's ever seen the Great Oz!
从来没人见过伟大的欧兹大法师!
Even l've never seen him!
甚至连我也从未见过他!
Well, then, how do you know there is one?
哦,那你怎么知道 哪里真的有这样一个人?
Because he's--
因为他是...
You're wasting my time!
你们在浪费我的时间!
Oh, please. Please, sir.
噢,拜托.拜托,先生
l've got to see the Wizard. The Good Witch of the North sent me.
我一定得见到大法师 北方好巫婆叫我来的
Prove it!
证明给我看!
She's wearing the ruby slippers that she gave her.
她穿着巫婆送给她的红宝石鞋
So she is!
所以她说的是真的!
Well, bust my buttons!
哦,想激怒我呀!
Why didn't you say that in the first place?
为什么你不一开始就这么说?
That's a horse of a different color!
那状况就完全不同了
Come on in!
快进来!
Cabby! Cabby!
马车夫!马车夫!
Just what you're looking for! Take you any place in the city, we does!
那就是你们在找的东西! 我们负责带你们到城里任何地方!
-Would you take us to see the Wizard? -The Wizard? The Wizard?
- 你会带我们去见大法师吗? - 大法师?大法师吗?
Yes, of course. But first l'll take you to a place...
是的,当然 但是我会先带你们到一个...
...where you can tidy up.
...能让你们梳洗的地方
Oh, thank you so much!
噢,真是太谢谢你了
We've been gone such a long time, and we feel so mess--
我们走了这么久的时间 觉得浑身脏兮兮的...
What kind of a horse is that?
那是什么品种的马?
-l've never seen a horse like that! -No, and never will again.
- 我从没见过那样的马! - 是的,而且以后再也不会见到
There's only one of him, and he's it.
这里只有一个它,而它就是它
He's the Horse of a Different Color you've heard tell about.
它就是那不同颜色的马(另一回事) 你曾经听说过
Ha-ha-ha! Ho-ho-ho!
∮哈..哈..哈!∮ ∮呵..呵..呵!∮
And a couple of tra-la-las
∮还有几个特啦啦∮
That's how we laugh the day away In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮那是我们怎么笑着过日子 在这欢乐的古老欧兹乐土∮
Bzz, bzz, bzz! Chirp, chirp, chirp!
∮哔吉吉,哔吉吉,哔吉吉! 啁啾,啁啾,啁啾!∮
And a couple of la-di-das
∮还有几个特啦啦∮
That's how the crickets crick all day In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮那是蟋蟀怎么鸣叫终日 在这欢乐的古老欧兹乐土∮
We get up at twelve And start to work at one
∮我们十二点起床,一点开始上班∮
Take an hour for lunch And then at two we're done
∮一个钟头吃饭,两点下班∮
Jolly good fun!
∮快活好玩!∮
Ha-ha-ha! Ho-ho-ho!
∮哈..哈..哈!∮ ∮呵..呵..呵!∮
And a couple of tra-la-las
∮还有几个特啦啦∮
That's how we laugh the day away In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮那是我们怎么笑着过日子 在这欢乐的古老欧兹乐土∮
Ha-ha-ha! Ho-ho-ho!
∮哈..哈..哈!∮ ∮呵..呵..呵!∮
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
∮哈..哈..哈..哈..哈!∮
That's how we laugh the day away With a--
∮那是我们怎么笑着过日子 ∮和一个...∮
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮在这欢乐的古老欧兹乐土∮
Pat, pat here Pat, pat there
∮用手轻拍,拍拍这里∮ ∮用手轻拍,拍拍哪里∮
And a couple of brand-new straws
∮还有些全新的稻草∮
That's how we keep you young and fair In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮那是我们怎么让你保持年轻光彩 在这欢乐的古老欧兹乐土∮
Rub, rub here Rub, rub there
∮磨擦,磨磨这里∮ ∮磨擦,磨磨哪里∮
Whether you're tin or bronze
∮不管你是锡或铜∮
That's how we keep you in repair In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮那是我们怎么帮你维修良好 在这欢乐的古老欧兹乐土∮
We can make a dimpled smile Out of a frown
∮我们能用皱纹做出有酒窝的微笑∮
Can you even dye my eyes To match my gown?
∮你们甚至能将我的眼楮染色 来搭配我的服装吗?∮
Jolly old town!
∮快活的老城镇!∮
Clip, clip here Clip, clip there
∮修剪,剪剪这里∮ ∮修剪,剪剪哪里∮
We give the roughest claws
∮我们送上最坚硬的爪子∮
That certain air of savoir-faire In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮那无疑是良好教养的外貌 在这欢乐的古老欧兹乐土∮
That's how we laugh the day away
∮那是我们怎么笑着过日子
With a ha-ha-ha
∮和一个哈..哈..哈...∮
In the Merry Old Land of Oz
∮在这欢乐的古老欧兹乐土∮
Who's her? Who's her?
她是谁?她是谁?
lt's the witch!
那是巫婆!
She's followed us here!
她跟踪我们到这里!
"Surrender, Dorothy."
"投降吧,桃乐丝."
Dorothy? Who's Dorothy?
桃乐丝?谁是桃乐丝?
-The Wizard will explain it! -To the Wizard!
- 大法师会解释它! - 到大法师那儿吧!
Oh, dear! Whatever shall we do?
Oh, dear! 噢,亲爱的!我们应该怎么做?
We better hurry if we're gonna see the Wizard!
如果我们想见到大法师 最好动作快点!
Here! Here, here! Everything is all right.
过来!过来,过来!一切都很正常
Stop that now, just--
现在停下来,只要...
lt's all right! Everything is all right!
没事的!一切都没事!
The Great and Powerful Oz has got matters well in hand.
伟大有力的大法师 已经完全控制住这些事了
l hope.
我希望
So you can all go home! There's nothing to worry about!
所以你们全部回家吧! 没什么好担心的!
Get out of here. Now go on! Go on home.
离开这里,马上离开!回家去
Go home.
回家去
We want to see the Wizard right away. All four of us.
我们要马上见大法师! 我们全部的四个人
Orders are, nobody can see the Great Oz! Not nobody, not nohow!
命令是,没有人能见大法师! 没有人,绝对不允许!
But, please! lt's very important.
拜托!那非常重要!
l got a permanent just for the occasion.
我得到的不变的命令 只能在重大典礼
Not nobody, not nohow!
没有任何人能见他,绝对不允许!
But she's Dorothy!
但她是桃乐丝!
The witch's Dorothy?
巫婆就是桃乐丝?
Well, that makes a difference.
好吧,那就不一样了
Just wait here. l'll announce you at once.
在这里等着,我会马上通知你们
Did you hear that? He'll announce us at once.
你们听到吗?他会马上通知我们
-l've as good as got my brain. -l can fairly hear my heart beating.
- 我感到像已得到我的头脑一样 - 我简直像已听到我的心在跳着
l'll be home for supper.
我将会在家吃着晚餐
ln another hour, l'll be king of the forest.
再过一个小时,我将变成森林之王
Long live the king!
长命的国王!
If I Were King of the Forest
∮如果我是森林之王∮
Not queen
∮不是皇后∮
Not duke
∮不是侯爵∮
Not prince
∮不是王子∮
My regal robes of the forest
∮我的森林帝袍∮
Would be satin
∮会是以绸缎制成∮
Not cotton
∮不是棉布∮
Not chintz
∮不是印花棉布∮
I'd command each thing Be it fish or fowl
∮我将统治每件事 不论是飞禽或走兽∮
With a woof!
∮用声低吼指挥!∮
And a woof!
∮用一声低吼!∮
And a royal growl
∮还有一种皇家的咆哮!∮
As I'd click my heel All the trees would kneel
∮当我的鞋跟喀嚓响起 所有的树将会下跪∮
And the mountains bow And the bulls kowtow
∮所有的山都将鞠躬∮ ∮雄兽们都将卑躬头叩头∮
And the sparrow would take wing
∮还有麻雀将会振翅高飞∮
If I
∮如果我∮
If I were king
∮如果我是个王∮
Each rabbit would show respect to me
∮每只兔子将对我显露敬畏之情∮
The chipmunks genuflect to me
∮花栗鼠们将对着我下跪∮
Though my tail would lash
∮虽然我的尾巴会鞭打处罚∮
I would show compash
∮我仍会显示∮
For every underling
∮对我臣民的怜悯之心∮
If I
∮如果我∮
If I were king
∮如果我是个王∮
Just king
∮就是个王∮
Monarch of all I survey
∮所有我所俯视之物的君王∮
Monarch
∮君王∮
Of all I survey
∮对所有我所俯视之物∮
lf you were king, you wouldn't be afraid of anything?
如果你是个王 你将不再惧怕任何事?
Not nobody, not nohow!
没有,绝对没有!
-Not even a rhinoceros? -lmposserous!
-- 即使是头犀牛? - 不可能!
-How about a hippopotamus? -l'd trash him from top to "bottom-us."
- 那河马行吗? - 我会从头到底痛殴他一顿
-Supposing you met an elephant? -l'd wrap him up in "cello-phant" !
- 假设你碰见一头大象呢? - 我会把它打包到玻璃纸里
-What if it were a brontosaurus? -l'd show him who's king of the forest!
- 那如果是雷龙呢? - 我会让它知道谁才是森林之王!
-How?
- 怎么样? - 什么怎么样?
Courage!
勇气啊!
What makes a king out of a slave?
什么让奴隶蜕化成国王?勇气!
What makes the flag on the mast to wave? Courage!
什么让桅杆上的旗帜飞扬?勇气!
What makes the elephant charge his tusk...
什么让大象用象牙发起攻击...
...in the misty mist or the dusky dusk?
...在朦胧不清的雾里 或在幽暗的薄暮中?
What makes the muskrat guard his musk? Courage!
什么让麝鼠敢于捍卫它的麝香?勇气!
What makes the sphinx the Seventh Wonder? Courage!
什么让斯芬克斯(人面狮身像) 成为七大奇迹?勇气!
What makes the dawn come up like thunder?
什么让黎明像雷声般砰然乍现?
Courage!
勇气!
What makes the Hottentot so hot?
什么让霍屯督人这么热情?
What puts the "ape" in apricot?
什么把猴子放在杏树中?
What have they got that l ain't got?
他们拥有什么是我没有的?
-Courage! -You can say that again.
- 勇气! - 你们能再说一遍吗?
The Wizard says go away!
大法师叫你们离开!
Go away?
离开?
Looks like we came a long way for nothing.
看来我们远道而来却一无所得
And l was so happy.
而且我还曾如此快乐
l thought l was on my way home.
我还以为我已经步向回家的路途了
Don't cry. We're gonna get you to the Wizard.
别哭.我们会让你见到大法师的
We certainly are.
我们一定会
Auntie Em was so good to me...
艾姆婶婶以前对我那么好...
...and l never appreciated it.
...而我从不知感激
Running away and hurting her feelings.
还离家出走,伤了她的心
Professor Marvel said she was sick.
马勃尔教授说她病了
She may be dying...
她可能将要死去...
...and it's all my fault.
...而那全是我的错
l'll never forgive myself.
我将永远不会原谅自己
Never, never, never.
永远,永远,永远
Please don't cry anymore.
请别再哭了
l'll get you into the Wizard somehow.
我会想个办法让你进到大法师哪里
Come on. l had an Aunt Em myself once.
来吧.我自己也曾经经历过一次 像艾姆婶婶这样的事情
Wait a minute, fellas.
等一下,伙伴们
l was just thinking, l don't want to see the Wizard this much.
我刚在想,我似乎不这么想见大法师
l better wait for you outside.
我最好还是在外面等你们
-What's the matter? -He's just scared again.
- 又怎么了? - 他只不过又害怕了
Don't you know the Wizard will give you courage?
难道你不知道大法师会给你勇气?
l'd be too scared to ask him for it.
我太害怕了 所以不敢开口要求他给我勇气
Well, then, we'll ask him for you.
好吧,那么我会帮你要求的
l'd sooner wait outside.
我宁愿待在外头
Why? Why?
为什么?为什么?
Because l'm still scared!
因为我还是感到害怕!
-What happened? -Somebody pulled my tail.
- 发生什么事? - 有人拉着我的尾巴
You did it yourself.
你自己拉的啦
Here.
过来
Come on.
走吧
Come forward!
走向前来!
Tell me when it's over!
当它结束时再告诉我!
Look at that. Look at that!
看看那个.看看那个!
l wanna go home!
我要回家!
l am Oz...
我是欧兹...
...the Great and Powerful!
...伟大和权威!
Who are you?
你们是什么人?
lf you please...
若是让您喜欢...
...l am Dorothy...
...我是桃乐丝...
...the small and meek.
...卑微而温顺的
We've come to ask you--
我们来请求您...
Silence!
安静!
Oh! Jiminy crickets!
噢!我的老天!
The Great and Powerful Oz...
伟大和威力的欧兹...
...knows why you have come.
...知道你们为什么而来
Step forward...
走向前...
...Tin Man!
...锡人!
You dare to come to me for a heart, do you?
你胆敢到这里向我要求颗心,是吗?
You clinking, clanking, clattering...
你这叮叮当当作响的...
...collection of caliginous junk!
...废弃旧物组合的废物!
Yes, sir.
是的,先生
Yes, Your Honor.
是的,阁下
You see...
你知道...
...a while back, we were walking down the Yellow Brick Road--
...不久之前,我们沿着黄砖道...
Quiet!
住嘴!
And you, Scarecrow...
还有你,稻草人...
...have the effrontery to ask for a brain...
...厚颜无耻的来求取一个脑...
...you billowing bale of bovine fodder!
...你这一大包牛饲料!
Yes, Your Honor. l mean, Your Excellency.
是的,阁下 我是说,尊贵的阁下
l mean, Your Wizardry!
我是说,尊贵的大法师!
Enough!
够了!
And you, Lion!
还有你,狮子!
Well?
喔?
You ought to be ashamed of yourself...
你应该为你自己感到羞愧...
...frightening him like that when he came to you for help!
...当他来请求你的帮助时 把他吓成那样子!
Silence...
安静...
...whippersnapper!
...傲慢的家伙!
The beneficent Oz has every intention of granting your requests.
仁慈的欧兹有意愿准许你们的请求...
What's that? What'd he say?
什么?他说了什么?
What'd he say?
他说了什么?
But first, you must prove yourselves worthy...
但首先,你们必须证明你们值得...
...by performing a very small task.
...完成一件小事来证明
Bring me the broomstick of the Witch of the West.
将西方巫婆的扫帚带来给我
But if we do that, we'll have to kill her to get it.
但为了取得扫帚,我们将必须杀了她
Bring me her broomstick...
带给我她的扫帚...
...and l'll grant your requests.
...而我将准许你们的请求
Now go!
现在离开吧!
But what if she kills us first?
但要是她先杀了我们呢?
l said go!
我说"离开"!
"l'd turn back if l were you."
"假如我是你,我会回头"
l believe there's spooks around here.
我相信这里到处都是幽灵
That's ridiculous!
那太荒谬了!
Spooks! That's silly.
幽灵!那太愚蠢了
Don't you believe in spooks?
你不相信有幽灵?
No. Why, only--
不.当然,只有...
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
l do believe in spooks.
我真的相信有幽灵!
l do, l do, l do, l do.
我相信,我相信,我相信,我相信
l do, l do, l do, l do, l do!
我真的相信有幽灵 我相信,我相信,我相信,我相信!
You'll believe in more than that before l'm finished with you.
在我消灭你们之前 你会宁愿去相信比那更多的东西
Take your army and bring me that girl and her dog.
带你的军队去将那女孩和她的狗 抓来给我
Do what you like with the others, but l want her alive.
其他人就随你高兴怎么处置 但是我要她活着
They'll give you no trouble. l promise you that.
他们不会给你惹麻烦的 我可以向你保证
l've sent a little insect on ahead to take the fight out of them.
我会让些小虫当先锋,将他们解决掉
Take special care of those slippers. l want those most of all.
要特别当心那红宝石鞋 那是我最想到的东西
Now, fly! Fly!
现在,飞吧!飞吧!
Bring me that girl and her slippers!
将女孩和她的红宝石鞋带来给我
Help! Help!
救命!救命!
Go away now!
马上滚开!
Toto! Toto! Help!
托托!托托!救命!
Help! Help! Help!
救命!救命!救命!
What happened to you?
你怎么了?
They tore my legs off and threw them over there!
他们把我的脚扯下丢到哪里!
Then they took my chest and threw it over there!
然后他们又拿走我的胸膛丢到哪里!
That's you all over.
你被丢的到处都是!
They sure knocked the stuffings out of you.
他们确实将填充物从你身体扯出来
Don't stand there. Put me together. We've got to find Dorothy!
别呆站在哪里!将我组合起来 我们必须去找桃乐丝!
Now, let's see....
嗯,让我瞧瞧....
What a nice little dog.
多么可爱的小狗啊
And you, my dear.
还有你,我亲爱的
What an unexpected pleasure.
多么意外的荣幸啊
lt's so kind of you to visit me in my loneliness.
在我孤独的时候来拜访我 你真是体贴啊
What are you gonna do with my dog? Give him back!
你想对我的狗怎么样? 把它还我!
All in good time, my little pretty.
别太着急了,我的小美人
All in good time.
别太着急了
Please give me back my dog.
请你把狗还我
Certainly, certainly...
当然,当然...
...when you give me those slippers.
...只要你把红宝石鞋给我
But the Good Witch told me not to.
但好巫婆告诉过我不能这么做
Very well.
那好吧
Throw that basket in the river.
把篮子丢到河里
No! You can have your old slippers, but give me back Toto!
不要!你可以拿走你的旧鞋子, 但是把托托还给我!
That's a good little girl.
那就对了,小女孩
l knew you'd see reason!
我知道你很明理的!
l'm sorry! l didn't do it. Can l still have my dog?
我很抱歉!我无法办不到 我是否仍能要回我的狗呢?
No! Fool that l am, l should have remembered...
不!我真是傻瓜 我应该要记得...
...those slippers will never come off...
...这鞋子永远无法脱下来...
...as long as you're alive.
...只要你还活着
But that's not what's worrying me. lt's how to do it.
但是那并不是我所困扰的 而是应该怎么做这件事
These things must be done delicately...
这些事必须很巧妙地完成...
...or you hurt the spell.
...否则你会被咒语所伤害
-Run, Toto, run! -Catch him, you fool!
- 跑,托托,快跑! - 抓住它,你这笨蛋!
Run, Toto, run!
快跑,托托,快跑!
He got away! He got away!
它跑掉了!它跑掉了!
Which is more than you will!
我不知道你们哪个应得多些!
Drat, you and your dog!
诅咒,你和你的狗!
You've been more trouble to me than you're worth.
你给我带来的麻烦远大于你的价值
But it'll soon be over now!
但是现在,那很快就会结束了!
Do you see that?
你看见这没?
That's how much longer you've got to be alive.
这就是你还能活着的时间
And it isn't long, my pretty. lt isn't long!
而那不会太久的,我的小美人 那不会太久的!
l can't wait forever to get those shoes!
我可不能等一辈子才拿到鞋子!
l'm frightened.
我很害怕
l'm frightened, Auntie Em!
我很害怕,艾姆婶婶!
Where are you?
你在哪里呢?
lt's me. lt's Auntie Em.
是我.那是艾姆婶婶
We're trying to find you. Where are you?
我们正在找你,你在哪里呢?
l'm here in Oz, Auntie Em.
我在欧兹这里,艾姆婶婶
l'm locked up in the Witch's castle...
我被关在巫婆的城堡里...
...and l'm trying to get home to you, Auntie Em!
...而我正在想办法回家找你 艾姆婶婶!
Oh, Auntie Em, don't go away!
噢,艾姆婶婶,别离开!
l'm frightened!
我很害怕!
Come back! Come back!
回来!回来!
"Auntie Em, Auntie Em! Come back!"
"艾姆婶婶,艾姆婶婶!回来!"
l'll give you Auntie Em, my pretty!
我会给你艾姆婶婶,我的美人!
Look! There's Toto!
看!托托在哪里!
Where'd he come from?
它从哪里来的?
Why, don't you see?
当然,难道你不明白?
He's come to take us to Dorothy.
它来带我们去找桃乐丝
Come on, fellas!
快点,伙伴们!
l hope my strength holds out.
我希望我的力量能够维持下去
l hope your tail holds out.
我希望你的尾巴够强韧
What's that?
那是什么?
That's the castle of the Wicked Witch!
那是坏巫婆的城堡!
-Dorothy's in that awful place? -l hate to think of her in there.
- 桃乐丝在这可怕的城堡里? - 我痛恨她在里面的想法
-We've got to get her out. -Don't cry now.
- 我们必须救她出来 - 现在别哭
We haven't got the oilcan, and you've been squeaking enough as it is.
我们没带着油罐 而你发出的嘎吱声好像蛮需要它的
Who's them? Who's them?
他们是谁?他们是谁?
-l've got a plan how to get in there. -Fine. He's got a plan.
- 我有个计划能进去 - 好极了.他有计划了
-And you're gonna lead us. -Yeah.
- 你必须带领我们 - 对啊
-Me? -Yes, you.
- 我? - 是的,你
-l gotta get her out of there? -That's right.
- 我要从哪里救她出来? - 是啊
All right, l'll go in there for Dorothy.
好吧,为了桃乐丝我会进去哪里
Wicked Witch or no Wicked Witch...
不管有没有坏巫婆...
...guards or no guards, l'll tear them apart.
...不管有没有警卫 我都会把他们撕成碎片
l may not come out alive, but l'm going in there.
也许我没办法活着出来 但我还是会进去哪里
-There's only one thing l want you to do. -What's that?
- 我只要求你们做一件事 - 什么事?
Talk me out of it.
当我失去知觉时跟我说话
-No, you don't! -Oh, no.
- 不,你别! - 噢,不要
-Now, wait a minute. -Up!
- 嗯,等等 - 上!
Come on, l've got another idea.
来吧,我想到另外一个主意了
Do you think it would be polite, dropping in like this?
你想的主意会受到欢迎吗 像顺道拜访之类的?
Where do we go now?
我们现在要去哪里?
There!
哪里!
Wait! We better make sure. Dorothy, are you in there?
等等!我们最好肯定一下 桃乐丝,你在哪里吗?
lt's us!
是我们!
Yes!
是的!
lt's me! She's locked me in!
是我!巫婆将我关在里面!
We gotta get her out! Open the door!
我们要救她出来!打开这门!
Oh, hurry! Please hurry!
噢,快点!请快点!
The hourglass is almost empty!
沙漏快要漏完了!
Stand back!
往后站!
l knew you'd come! l knew you would!
我就知道你们会来!我就知道你们会!
Hurry, we've got no time to lose!
快点,我们快没时间了!
Going so soon?
这么快就要走了?
l wouldn't hear of it.
我可不是这么听说的
Why, my little party's just beginning.
当然,我的小宴会才刚要开始
Trapped. Trapped like mice...rats!
我们被设计了 像抓老鼠的...陷阱!
That's right. Don't hurt them right away.
对极了.别马上伤害他们
We'll let them think about it a little first.
我们要让他们先稍微的考虑一下
Seize them! Seize them!
抓住他们!抓住他们!
Stop them, you fools!
阻止他们,你们这些笨蛋!
There they go! Now we've got them!
他们往哪里去了! 现在我们会逮到他们的!
Half you go this way, half you go that way.
你们一半走这条路,你们走那条路
Hurry! Hurry!
快点!快点!
Where do we go now?
现在我们要往哪里走?
This way. Come on!
这条路.快点!
Back! Back!
回去!回去!
Well!
很好!
Ring-around the rosie, a pocket full of spears!
将玫瑰围个圈 一小块地方充满了刺
Thought you'd be pretty foxy, didn't you?
你认为你会是只可爱的狐狸吗?
The last to go will see the first three go before her.
她将会是最后一个死的 所以将会目睹其他三人的下场
And her mangy little dog too!
还有她那a脏的狗也一样!
How about a little fire, Scarecrow?
来点小火怎样,稻草人?
Help! l'm burning! l'm burning! lt's burning!
救命!我着火了!我着火了! 它烧起来了!
Don't touch that water!
别碰那水!
You cursed brat! Look what you've done!
你这可恶的小家伙! 看看你干了什么好事!
l'm melting! Melting!
我在溶化!溶化了!
What a world! What a world!
这是什么样的世界!这是什么样的世界!
Who would've thought a good little girl like you...
谁会想到像你一样乖巧的小女孩...
...could destroy my beautiful wickedness?
...能够毁灭我完美的邪恶?
Look out! Look out!
注意啊!注意啊!
l'm going.
我要死了
She's dead. You've killed her.
她死了.你已经杀了她
l didn't mean to kill her.
我并不是故意要杀死她
Really, l didn't.
真的,我不是有心的
lt's just that he was on fire.
只不过是他着火了,事情就这样发生了
Hail to Dorothy! The Wicked Witch is dead!
桃乐丝万岁!坏巫婆死了!
Hail! Hail to Dorothy!
万岁!桃乐丝万岁!
The broom.
这扫帚
-May we have it? -Please. And take it with you.
- 我们能拥有它吗? - 请你们拿走它吧
Thank you so much!
非常谢谢你!
Now we can go tell the Wizard the Wicked Witch is dead!
现在我们能回去跟大法师说 坏巫婆已经死了
The Wicked Witch is dead!
坏巫婆死了!
Can l believe my eyes?
我能相信我的眼楮吗?
Why have you come back?
你们带了什么回来?
Please, sir. We've done what you told us.
请看,先生 我们已经完成了您的吩咐
We've brought you the broomstick of the Wicked Witch.
我们把坏巫婆的扫帚带回来给您
We melted her.
我们还溶解了她
You liquidated her, eh? Very resourceful.
你们消除了她?非常的机智
Yes, sir.
是的,先生
So we'd like you to keep your promise to us, if you please.
所以我们希望您遵守您对我们的承诺 如果您满意的话
Not so fast. Not so fast!
别急.别急!
l'll have to give the matter a little thought.
我必须要思考一下这事
Go away and come back tomorrow.
先离开,明天再来
Tomorrow?
明天?
But l want to go home now!
但是我想马上回家!
You've had plenty of time already.
你已经有过充分的时间
Do not arouse the wrath of the Great and Powerful Oz!
别激怒伟大与威力的欧兹!
l said come back tomorrow!
我说了,明天再来!
lf you were really great and powerful, you'd keep your promises.
如果你真的伟大与威力 你应该遵守您的承诺
Do you presume to criticize the Great Oz?
你在质疑评判伟大的欧兹吗?
You ungrateful creatures!
你这忘恩负义的动物!
Think yourselves lucky that l'm giving you audience tomorrow...
你们要感到幸运 我让你们明天来谒见我...
...instead of 20 years from now!
...而不是20年后!
The Great Oz has spoken!
伟大的欧兹是这么说的!
Pay no attention to that man behind the curtain.
别管那个在布帘之后的人
The Great and-- Oz has spoken.
伟大和... 欧兹是这么说的!
Who are you?
你是谁?
Well, l am the Great and Powerful Wizard of Oz.
好吧,我就是伟大与威力的欧兹大法师
You are?
你就是?
l don't believe you!
我才不相信你!
l'm afraid it's true. There's no other Wizard except me.
很不幸这是真的 这里除了我之外,并没有其他巫师
You humbug!
你这个骗子!
Yes, that's exactly so. l'm a humbug.
是的,那的确是.我是个骗子
You're a very bad man!
你是个很坏的人!
No, my dear. l'm a very good man.
不,亲爱的.我是个很好的人
l'm just a very bad wizard.
却是个很差劲的巫师
What about the heart you promised Tin Man?
那你答应锡人的心怎么办?
And the courage you promised Cowardly Lion?
还有你答应狮子的的勇气呢?
And Scarecrow's brain?
还有稻草人的头脑呢?
Why, anybody can have a brain. That's a very mediocre commodity.
噢,每个人都有一颗头脑 它是再平凡不过的东西
Every pusillanimous creature that crawls on the earth...
每只卑微的动物 不管是在地上爬的...
...or slinks through slimy seas has a brain.
...或者潜行于海里的 都有一颗脑袋
Back where l come from, we have universities...
在我原来生活的地方 我们有许多大学...
...seats of great learning, where men go to become great thinkers.
...大量知识存放的地方 人们到哪里学习,以便成为伟大思想家
They think deep thoughts, and with no more brains than you have.
他们能深入思考哲理 他们并没有比你更加聪明
But they have one thing you haven't got. A diploma.
但是他们有一样是你没有的... 一张文凭
Therefore, by virtue of the authority vested in me...
因此,根据我所被赋予的权利...
...by the Universitatus Committeeatum E Pluribus Unum...
...得自普鲁瑞本士大学董事会...
...l hereby confer upon you...
...我在此授与你...
...the honorary degree of Th.D.
...Th.D.荣誉学位
Th.D.?
Th.D.是什么?
That's Doctor of Thinkology.
就是"思想学博士"
The sum of the square roots of two sides of an isosceles triangle...
一个等腰三角形两边的平方根和...
...is equal to the square root of the remaining side.
...等于另一边的平方根
Oh, joy! Rapture!
噢,天啊!真令人欣喜!
l've got a brain!
我得到我的头脑了!
How can l thank you enough?
我要如何才能报答你呢?
Well, you can't. As for you, my fine friend...
喔,你不需要! 而你,我的好朋友...
...you're a victim of disorganized thinking.
...你是混乱思想的受害者
You are under the delusion that because you run away from danger...
你受困于一种错觉 认为你面对危险会逃跑是因为...
...you have no courage. You're confusing courage with wisdom.
...你没有勇气 你把勇气与智慧搞混了
Back where l come from, we have men who are called "heroes."
回到我原来生活之处 我们有一种叫做"英雄"的人
Once a year, they take their fortitude out of mothballs...
每年一度,他们会拿出尘封的坚忍勇气...
...and parade it down the main street.
...列队在大街上游行
And they have no more courage than you have.
他们并不比你勇敢
But they have one thing that you haven't got. A medal.
但是他们有一样是你没有的... 一枚勋章
Therefore...
因此...
...for meritorious conduct, extraordinary valor...
...为了你勇敢的带领, 非凡的气魄...
...conspicuous bravery against wicked witches...
...出色的勇气 都表现在在对抗坏巫婆时...
...l award you the Triple Cross.
...我授与你"三重十字勋章"
You are now a member of the Legion of Courage.
你现在勇气军团的一员了
Shucks, folks, l'm speechless.
呸,各位,我是言语无法形容的
As for you, my galvanized friend, you want a heart.
还有你,我镀锌的朋友,你要求颗心
You don't know how lucky you are not to have one.
你不知道你没有心是多么的幸运
Hearts will never be practical until they can be made unbreakable.
心一点都不实用 除非它们能被做成牢不可破
But l still want one.
但是我还是想要一颗
Back where l come from, there are men who do nothing all day but good deeds.
回到我原来生活之处 哪里有人除了行善外,终日无所适事
They are called phil--
他们被称为爱...
Good-deed-doers. And their hearts are no bigger than yours.
慈善家. 可是他们的情感也没比你多
But they have one thing you haven't got. A testimonial.
但是他们有一样你没有的东西... 一纸褒扬状
Therefore, in consideration of your kindness...
因此,在考虑过你的仁慈...
...l take pleasure at this time in presenting you...
...我很荣幸在这里呈递给你...
...with a small token of our esteem and affection.
用一件小纪念品 表达我们的尊重及感情
And remember, my sentimental friend...
请记住,我的金属朋友...
...that a heart is not judged by how much you love...
...爱心并不是以你爱多少人来评估...
...but by how much you are loved by others.
...而是以有多少人爱你来判定
lt ticks!
它在滴答响!
Listen! Look, it ticks!
听着!看啊,它在滴答响!
Read what my medal says. "Courage."
读读我的奖章怎么说的..."勇气"
Ain't it the truth!
可那不就是事实吗!
Oh, they're all wonderful.
噢,它们都棒极了
Hey, what about Dorothy?
嘿,那桃乐丝呢?
Yes, how about Dorothy?
是啊,桃乐丝怎么办?
Dorothy next.
下一个是桃乐丝呀
l don't think there's anything in that black bag for me.
我不认为黑袋子里有任何能帮我的
You force me into a cataclysmic decision.
你逼我做一个重大的决定
The only way to get Dorothy to Kansas is for me to take her myself.
我必须亲自带桃乐丝回堪萨斯 这是唯一的办法
Oh, will you? Could you?
噢,你会吗?你可以吗?
But are you clever enough to manage it?
但是操控它你够灵巧吗?
Child, you cut me to the quick!
孩子,你伤了我的感情了!
l'm an old Kansas man myself...
我可是个老堪萨斯人...
...born and bred in the western wilderness...
...诞生及成长于西部荒野之地...
...premier balloonist par excellence to the Miracle Wonderland Carnival Company.
...奇迹仙境巡回表演公司的 最杰出之首席气球驾驶员
Until one day, while performing feats of stratospheric skill...
直到有一天在表演同温层操控技巧...
...never before attempted by civilized man...
...文明世界从没人尝试过...
...an unfortunate phenomena occurred.
...一个不幸的现象发生了
The balloon failed to return to the fair.
气球无法顺利的回到顺气流
lt did?
它发生了?
Weren't you frightened?
那不会让你害怕吗?
You are talking to a man who has laughed in the face of death...
你在谈论一个曾当面讥笑死神...
...sneered at doom and chuckled at catastrophe. l was petrified.
...嘲笑厄运和在大灾难仍旧大笑的人 我完成吓呆了
Suddenly the wind changed...
突然间风向变了...
...and the balloon floated down into this noble city...
...气球漂浮下来 进入这高贵的城市...
...where l was instantly acclaimed Oz, the first wizard deluxe!
...欧兹的人们立刻拥立我为 首位高级大法师!
Times being what they were, l accepted the job...
经过他们几次请求,我接受了工作...
...retaining my balloon against the advent of a quick getaway.
...留下我的气球 抗拒立刻逃走的念头
And in that balloon, dear Dorothy...
而用那气球,亲爱的桃乐丝...
...you and l will return to the land of E Pluribus Unum.
...你和我将回到那唯一的土地
My friends. l mean, my friends!
我的朋友们.我说,我的朋友们!
This is positively the finest exhibition ever to be shown...
这绝对是前所未有的展示...
...be that as it may.
...尽它所能
l, your Wizard per ardua ad alta...
我,你们的大法师 #破 啊丢啦 噎得 噎而踏...#
...am about to embark upon a hazardous...
...将搭船去从事一次冒险的...
...and technically unexplainable journey...
...和从技术上无法解释的旅行...
...into the outer stratosphere!
...以进入外同温层!
To confer, converse...
经过与我的巫师朋友们...
...and otherwise hobnob with my brother wizards.
...亲密的协商讨论
And l hereby decree that until what time...
我在此颁布命令
...if any, that l return...
在我回来之前...
...the Scarecrow, by virtue of his highly superior brains...
...将由有着优越头脑的稻草人
...shall rule in my stead...
代替我统治...
...assisted by the Tin Man, by virtue of his magnificent heart...
...并由善良的锡人及勇敢的狮子
...and the Lion, by virtue of his courage.
从旁协助
Obey them as you would me.
像服从我一样的服从他们
Thank you.
谢谢你
Come back!
托托,回来!
Don't go without me. l'll be right back.
别丢下我一个人走,我会马上回来
Stop that dog!
拦住那只狗!
This is a highly irregular procedure. This is absolutely unprecedented!
这是非常不规则的程序 而且绝对是史无前例的!
Ruined my exit!
打开我的出口!
Come back! Come back!
回来!回来!
Don't go without me! Please come back!
别丢下我!回来,拜托!
l can't come back! l don't know how it works!
我无法回去!我不知道这怎么操作!
Goodbye, folks!
再见,各位!
Goodbye!
再见!
Now l'll never get home.
现在我再也回不了家了
Stay with us then, Dorothy.
留下来跟我们在一起,桃乐丝
We all love you.
我们都爱你
We don't want you to go.
我们都不想你离开
That's very kind of you...
你真是体贴...
...but this could never be like Kansas.
...但是这里永远不会像堪萨斯一样
Auntie Em must have stopped wondering what happened to me by now.
一定要让艾姆婶婶别再担心 到底我发生什么事
Oh, Scarecrow, what am l going to do?
噢,稻草人,我该怎么办?
Look!
看!
Here's someone who can help you!
这里有人能帮助你!
Will you help me? Can you help me?
你会帮我吗?你能帮我吗?
You don't need help any longer.
你再也不需要求助了
You've always had the power to go back to Kansas.
你早就有力量回去堪萨斯了
l have?
我有?
Why didn't you tell her before?
你之前为什么不告诉她?
Because she wouldn't have believed me. She had to learn it for herself.
因为她不会相信我 她必须靠自己学会
What have you learned, Dorothy?
你学到了什么,桃乐丝?
l think that it...
我想那是...
...that it wasn't enough just to want to see Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
...光想见到亨利叔叔和艾姆婶婶 是不够的
And it's that if l ever go looking for my heart's desire again...
还有如果我未曾 再次寻找我心底的渴望...
...l won't look any further than my own back yard...
...我将无法看得比我家后院更远...
...because if it isn't there...
...因为如果它不在我心里...
...l never really lost it to begin with.
...我从来就没真的失去过它
ls that right?
是这样吗?
That's all it is.
始终就是那样
But that's so easy! l should've thought of it for you.
但是那是如此容易! 我早该帮你想到才对
l should've felt it in my heart.
我早就应该感觉到它在我心底
She had to find it out for herself.
她必须自己去发现这件事
Now those magic slippers will take you home in two seconds.
现在那红宝石鞋会在两秒内带你回家
-Toto too? -Toto too.
- 托托也是? - 托托也是
-Now? -Whenever you wish.
- 马上? - 任何时间,只要你想要
Oh, dear.
噢,亲爱的
That's too wonderful to be true!
那真是美妙得不像真的!
lt's gonna be so hard to say goodbye.
没想到道别会是这么困难
l love you all too.
我爱你们所有人
Goodbye, Tin Man.
再见,锡人
Don't cry.
别哭
You'll rust so dreadfully.
你会锈得一塌糊涂的
Here. Here's your oilcan.
拿去.这是你的油罐
Goodbye.
再见
Now l know l've got a heart...
现在我确定我得到了一颗心了...
...because it's breaking.
...因为它正在破碎了
Goodbye, Lion.
再见,狮子
l know it isn't right...
我知道那是不对的...
...but l'm gonna miss the way you used to holler for help...
...但是我还是会怀念 这一路来你大喊救命的样子...
...before you found your courage.
...在你找到你的勇气之前
l would never have found it if it hadn't been for you.
如果不是你,我可能永远找不到它
l think l'll miss you most of all.
我想我会最怀念你
Are you ready now?
你准备好了没?
Say goodbye, Toto.
说再见,托托
Yes, l'm ready now.
是的,我准备好了
Then close your eyes...
现在闭上你的眼睛...
...and tap your heels together three times...
...并且用你的鞋跟相敲三次...
...and think to yourself...
...并在内心告诉自己...
..."There's no place like home.
..."没有地方能跟家一样
There's no place like home."
没有地方能跟家一样
Wake up, honey.
醒醒,宝贝
Dorothy, dear. lt's Aunt Em, darling.
桃乐丝,亲爱的.是艾姆婶婶,亲爱的
Oh, Auntie Em, it's you!
噢,艾姆婶婶,真的是你!
-Yes, darling. -Hello there! Anybody home?
- 是的,亲爱的 - 哈,您好!有人在家吗?
l dropped by because l heard the little girl got caught in the big--
我顺道来拜访,因为我听说小女孩 被大龙卷风抓走了...
She seems all right now.
现在看起来她没事了
She got quite a bump.
她被大力碰撞过
We kind of thought she was gonna leave us.
我们还有点担心她会离我们而去
But l did leave you. That's just the trouble.
但是我真的离开了你 不过那是件麻烦事儿
And l tried to get back for days!
我试了好多天才能回来
There, there, lie quiet now.
哪里,哪里,现在乖乖的躺好
You just had a bad dream.
你只不过是做了个恶梦
Remember me...
记得我吗...
...your old pal, Hunk?
...你的老伙伴,杭克?
And me...
还有我...
...Hickory?
...海格瑞?
You couldn't forget my face, could you?
你不会忘了我的脸吧,你会吗?
But it wasn't a dream.
但是那不是个梦
lt was a place.
它是一个真实的地方
And you and you and you...
而你,你,你,你...
...and you were there.
...还有你也在哪里
But you couldn't have been, could you?
但是你们不可能在哪里的,不是吗?
We dream lots of silly things when we--
我们梦到许多无聊的事情,当我们...
No, Aunt Em, this was a real, truly live place.
不,艾姆婶婶,这是真的,活生生的地方
And l remember that some of it wasn't very nice...
我还记其中有些不是很好...
...but most of it was beautiful.
...但大部分都很美丽
But just the same, all l kept saying to everybody was, "l want to go home!"
但是我一直对每个人说同样的话 "我要回家"
And they sent me home.
而他们就送我回来了
Doesn't anybody believe me?
没有人相信我吗?
Of course we believe you, Dorothy.
我们当然相信你,桃乐丝
But anyway, Toto, we're home!
无论怎样,托托,我们到家了!
Home!
家!
And this is my room...
这是我的房间...
...and you're all here.
...还有你们全在这里
And l'm not going to leave here ever, ever again...
我将永远永远不再离开这里...
...because l love you all.
...因为我爱你们
And oh, Auntie Em...
还有,噢,艾姆婶婶...
...there's no place like home!
...没有任何地方能像家一样!